+49 151 71999620 www.nicdent.com

Nic Dent

contact@nicdent.com

UX Designer - Berlin

Over 8 years of expertise as a UX Designer and Front End Developer in Melbourne and London. I combine strategic thinking, creative design with a strong understanding of technology and user experience.

I thrive in agile teams that work with Lean methodologies.

Visa status - German working holiday Visa (Exp - 22/07/2016).

EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Designer - MYOB (Melbourne - 1000+ employees) 2013-2015

MYOB has a large range of products used by over 1 million businesses in Australia and New Zealand. The user is always the centre of the iterative design process at MYOB and user testing was seen as essential for all projects.

UX Designer within an Agile scrum team with Lean methodologies. The team worked with many other teams to provide solutions to help solve a range of business problems for customers on many different devices.

- Lead UX Designer of admin and onboarding changes to a small business website builder with over 50,000 customers.
- Lead UX Designer of a online invoicing presentation app to be used by over
 1 million businesses.
- Lead UX Designer on integration and onboarding of new online invoicing for multiple apps including a desktop app, web app, IOS app and android app.
- Facilitation of user testing through the design and build process to measure the success and failures of new features.
- Collaborating with other MYOB UI & UX designers to establish company wide design standards.

UI/UX Designer - ME Bank (Melbourne - 800+ employees) 2012-2013

I was brought into the transformation team at ME Bank to analyse a completed custom built web application that was lacking interface design and usability.

- Workshop facilitation with PM's, developers and other stakeholders to identify system constraints and opportunities to improve.
- Facilitation of user testing of current systems including observation, interviews & task completion evaluations with existing staff using system.
- Lead UX Designer of design guidelines to be implemented on current systems and to be utilised on any newly built systems for internal staff.

SKILLS

Lean UX

Agile methodologies

Wireframing

Rapid Prototyping - low to hi fidelity.

Interface design - Mobile, Web & Desktop app.

Interaction Design

Information Architecture

Responsive Web Design

User Testing - Planning, facilitation, Analysis & presentation.

Analytics analysis

Client engagement

Marketing strategy

Leadership

Documentation (Lean)

Workshop facilitation

Pairing - Design, Coding & Testing.

Coding - HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS & Javascript.

Frameworks - Bootstrap, Foundation & Jquery.

TOOLS

Pencils, pens, paper, whiteboards, walls...

Atlassian - Jira, Confluence, Hipchat & SourceTree.

Photoshop, Sketch, Illustrator, Balsamiq, Axure RP, Invision.

Sublime text

UI/UX Designer & Front End Developer - 2007-2012

The Group (London - 50+ employees),

Steel (London - 30+ employees),

Immersive (Melbourne - 30+ employees),

3Floorsup (Melbourne - 4-6 employees).

The first 6 years of my career where split between Melbourne and London working as either a UI/UX Designer or Front End Developer with a variety of web agencies. Projects ranged from small businesses to large corporation

- Lead Designer and Front end dev of a online T-shirt design competition start-up.
- Lead Designer and Front end dev of the corporate website for world wide maintenance group CE Property services.
- Lead Designer and Front end dev of Mckenzie's foods website.
- Front end developer for websites of large companies in the FTSE 100 that are within the finance, resources and commercial sectors.

EDUCATION

RMIT University - Bachelor of Design (Multimedia) - 2003 - 2007

RECENT CONFERENCES & WORKSHOPS

UX Australia Conference

YOW - Australian Developer Conference

Lean UX workshop - Jeff Gothelf

Ideation and Product Design workshop - ZURB